Hello everybody. It's high noon in old
Cheyenne. So I'd like to call the
January 21st, 2026 meeting of the
finance committee to order. Uh if you're
in the room, uh turn your electronic
devices to silent or vibrate. Uh if
you're making public comment, use the
online, use the raised hand function,
and our staff will allow you to unmute
yourself in person, approach the podium,
turn the line on uh to the screen, and
we do have one additional item on our
agenda today. And after that there will
be no more business discussed.
Um as always all communication goes
through the chair. And with that clerk
read the first item please.
>> Number 8B application for transfer of
ownership of retail liquor license filed
with the city clerk's office for AC's
range LLC doing business as AS's range
1505 Pioneer Avenue Cheyenne Wyoming.
License currently held by FNG
Corporation doing business as the green
door.
>> Staff report.
>> Mr. Chairman, members of the committee,
Kylie Soden, city clerk. Before you is
an application for the transfer of
ownership of a retail license from FNG
Corporation to AC's range doing business
as AC's range located at 1505 Pioneer
Avenue. The application has been
reviewed by the appropriate city
departments as well as the Wyoming
liquor division and um requirements have
been met and I would be happy to answer
any questions.
>> Any questions for staff?
Any public comment?
>> Mr. Chairman, I'm Ben Trrowline of FNG
Corporation, 255 story boulevard, and I
just wanted to say I'm here to support
the sale and answer any questions. I
think it'll be the transfer will be a
great use of the license.
>> Good afternoon, Mr. Chairman. My name is
JB Coons. uh the owner operator of Aces
Range LLC and I am also here to stand
for any questions that you may have in
the use of this liquor license.
>> No questions.
Miss Counsel
Bremer Coun 6210 Bremer Road Cheyenne
Wyoming. I am also a member of the LLC
ASUS range handle the financial
transactions.
Mr. Chairman, we would appreciate your
favorable consideration
and note that it's really kind of a fun
thing that the Troutwine family is many
generations in Wyoming as is the Brimmer
family. So this is an ongoing business
of in my case the third and fourth
generations. I stand for any questions.
Mr. Chairman
>> not seeing any questions. Can I get a
motion?
>> Mr. Chair, I move to approve.
>> Second, Mr. Chair.
>> Motion by Councilman White. Second by
Councilman Wolf. Any other public
comment or uh comments from the
committee?
>> Uh Mr. Chair, I'll keep my comments very
brief both on this item and in the item
uh that will be immediately following.
Uh both of these applicants for my
colleague Mr. Wolf and Dr. Emmens who is
online. They both took part in a very
extensive
uh process 5 years ago where we heard 10
applicants make their presentations to
us during COVID. Um at the when we were
having our meetings at the um Laramie
County School District boardroom. Um
both of these applicants have done
done great things for our community, I
think, with their businesses. Um
although I still haven't improved my
golf game JP by coming to your uh
establishment. However, I'll keep
trying. Um but I think uh I think it's a
very good use of of uh the license to to
have a local business uh keep it and so
I'm very happy to support it.
>> Councilman Wolf. Uh Mr. Chairman,
through you. Thank you very much. Um I
echo um Mr. White's comments. I
obviously wasn't on the council uh five
years ago, but um I've known um the uh
the courts former Senator Coons for very
very long time. And um and uh I've uh
and for the just for the audience is we
we had a public hearing uh before the
the council uh just recently and we we
we've got a great description of uh the
Asus Bar operation and um that sounds
like a terrific uh business uh in a core
part of the city and um I'm uh I'm more
than happy to support this and thank you
for bringing it forward. Thank you, Mr.
Triwine as well. So, thank you.
>> Uh Dr. Emmens, anything?
>> I would just agree with my colleagues
that I'm excited to have a a young
person in the community starting a
business and moving forward. It's a
great example of what we can do with our
our youth in Cheyenne. So, thank you.
With that, I'll call for a vote.
>> I
recommendation of the finance committee
to the governing body next Monday will
be to approve. Next item, please.
>> Number 8 C. Application for a transfer
of ownership of retail liquor license
filed with the city clerk's office for
Westb Edge LLC doing business as Westby
Edge Brewing, 714 West 20th Street,
Cheyenne, Wyoming. License currently
held by Scooter Scoreboard, Inc.
Stafford.
>> Mr. Chairman, Kylie Soden, city clerk,
before you is an application for the
transfer of ownership of a retail liquor
license from Scooter Scoreboard, Inc. to
Westby Edge LLC, doing business as
Westby Edge Brewing, located at 714 West
20th Street. The application has been
reviewed by the appropriate city
departments as well as the Wyoming
Liquor Division, and all requirements
have been met. under the current license
holder. The license will reach the
two-year expiration period for an
inoperational parked status on January
24th. In order to meet this deadline,
the application is being presented for
consideration at the January 23rd
special meeting of the governing body
and I will be happy to answer any
questions.
>> Anyone on the committee got questions
for staff?
>> Council Wolf.
>> Uh Mr. Chairman, through you. Um, I I
would just like to thank you uh thank
your office uh for bringing this to us
and and um it was um it's great to be
able to get this done before it uh
expires and um thanks for all that
you've done to support it.
Let's go to public comment.
Turn that microphone off.
>> Mr. Chairman, thank you. Uh, committee
members, thank you for the opportunity.
Darren Westby, 714,
uh, West 20th Street, Westby Edge
Brewing. With me today is my daughter,
uh, who's also a partner in the
business. Uh, she's also our brewer, uh,
Brennan Westby. uh and I couldn't get my
wife uh out of court so she stayed over
in Laramie. Uh but uh Miesa Westby is
also a partner and um just uh real
briefly and I'll try to be brief because
I know you have a lot on the agenda but
uh just to give a little bit of history
and a little background. A couple of you
were on the committee uh on the council,
some of you were not, but uh some
impetus on why we're here. Um,
back in 2019, uh, my Frontier Days time
frame was coming down. I was ending my
last two years on the board of directors
out at Cheyenne Frontier Days. I've ran
every volunteer position out there. Um,
culminating to Hall of Fame a couple
years ago. So, pretty much that that
time frame was winding down for us. But
this community has been so good to me
and my family. We felt that we needed to
have one more opportunity to give back
to this community. And so we looked for
the next public you know community
involvement. And at the time the Reed
rail corridor was just uh kicking
started with the marketing plan and you
know the sixth penny was going hot and
heavy and so we said downtown
revitalization is our next community
involvement. We had no idea what we were
going to build but we were going to do
something. Uh we put our house on the
market thinking we had six months to
figure out that plan. Uh fortunately,
somebody was telling us it was the right
move. It sold in a day and a half. So it
expedited all of our all of our mindset
on what we were doing. Um luckily both
my wife and I really love beer and going
to breweries. So we said, "Well, how
hard could it be to build a brewery? Um
it's not that easy." But um we found,
you know, build a bar, it'll be great,
they said. Um
um but it it's awesome. Um you know, we
found the property down on on right on
the Reed Rail corridor. Great location
on 20th Street. Um put an offer in uh
and was accepted. Um halfway in between
here and Vegas, just like anytime you
want to make a good sound business
decision as adults, you just road trip
to Vegas. Uh but I think in Windover we
got the we got the contract signed
electronically and so we had a great
weekend. On the way back all we did um
was design the property and it was fun
to be able to spend 12 hours kind of
sketching out the layout, the business
plan. It was just so much fun. Um but uh
the sale took place February 2020. Uh
and then the world stopped and so we
still had a lot of work to do. Uh we're
not wealthy people. We're both state
employees. Uh we're not developers. We
don't have lots of money to to invest.
And so we rolled up our sleeves. I went
and got 14 class D contractor's licenses
and we went to town for the next three
and a half years to build that property
up. Uh it was a labor of love, a lot of
blood, sweat, and a lot of tears. Uh but
it was uh obviously it's working, right?
So, um, we opened up in June of 23 and,
uh, she produced her first beer in
October of that same month or that same
year. Um, so it's been fun. It's uh the
intent was to create a space that we not
necessarily didn't have, but how do we
exemplify why a lot of us go south for
an experience and try to create that
similar experience up here to hopefully
entice people to stay here, but uh
selfishly as a kind of a tourism guy, I
like to bring people up here because
Cheyenne has a lot to offer. And if we
can kind of give them what they're used
to down there, they'll take the trip.
And we got a great brewery scene here in
Cheyenne. So, we thought, what the heck?
Let's give that a shot. And it work.
It's working. You look at the downtown
and the western side of this uh city,
the developments going on. It's not just
us. I mean, I'd selfish if I said it
was. I mean, we got some family me
friends that uh bought the grain
elevator because of the project that was
going on. Blacktooth started up uh
during CO as well. Um, you got the that
great apartment complex going on right
up here. The downtown livability is
growing and it's going to be
exponential. It's going to be
transformational and what's going on.
So, we're really proud to be a part of
it. And at some point, the original plan
was to put four town homes on that
eastern dirt lot that we have there to
get more downtown livability. And
someday hopefully we'll get to get to
working on that. But we're, like I said,
we're pr proud to bring thousands of
people downtown every week. Um, happy to
give them a reason to come downtown.
Happy to have a reason to stay downtown.
Uh, and hopefully, you know, come full
circle with this license in the original
plan back in 2020 was to have a package
liquor in this area that we're um
thinking about doing. Sorry, I have
handouts.
Um, and so it's kind of fun, like I said
in the council meeting to to come full
circle. Uh, come go back to having that
package liquor. Originally, we always
thought about having a potential mini
market in that area. Um, as well,
knowing that the livability is starting
to grow, uh, giving uh, the desert that
we have down in the downtown area, we
got a couple that are popping up, which
is great. Um but to give another part of
the livability the opportunity to go get
an essential if they need it uh within
walking distance is kind of the the
plan. So with the use of the licenses uh
as shown in the drawings there is on
that south part of our what we call the
event space turn that into a package
liquor uh as well as a mini market.
uh have the ability to cater. Like I
said in the meeting, our our oldest
daughter is an event planner uh as
another side hustle for her. Uh and so
she could utilize the catering license
with her business as well. And then
operationally uh just having the ability
to not have to have the kitchen open all
hours, which we know uh I can show the
data. uh 9:00 on on a Friday and
Saturday, it's not a whole lot of food
being sh um cooked on in the oven. So,
not to say we wouldn't allow, you know,
some chips and salsa or something easy
that the servers can do, but uh that
gives us that flexibility. And then
obviously with the bar and grill
license, the 60/40 split creates a a
potential uh issue for us as well. And
so, Mr. Chairman, I talked probably
longer than I should have, but uh
obviously we're pretty proud of what we
built. Uh pretty proud of what we have
to offer the city of Cheyenne and really
uh appreciate your consideration on the
transfer. And I too would like to echo
your comments, Councilman, on the
assistance with the clerk's office on
getting um the timing that we had. uh it
was herculean to get everything done in
the short amount of time that we had to
get it done. So, appreciate that and I
would stand for any questions. Thank
you. It's a great local family uh
success story as was the previous item.
And uh do we have any questions from the
committee to the applicant?
No further public comment online.
We'll go call for a motion.
>> Mr. Chair, I move to approve. I second.
>> Motion to approve by Councilman White,
seconded by Councilman Wolf. Uh any
further discussion?
>> Uh Mr. Chair, uh through you. Thank you.
Um I I just like to compliment uh the
Westby family um for this. Um I I mean
it's a it's a great great addition. Uh
I'm glad that uh this worked out the way
it did. Um, it's reflective, I think, of
of the decisions by the council to
really try and maximize the the
beneficial use of these licenses. Um,
and um I and please, Mr. Westby, don't
ever apologize for telling us about what
you're doing. I I think it's great and I
think it's great for the public to to
hear that, too. So, thank you um for all
of your efforts and and your investment.
Um, and thank you, Brandon, for all that
you've been doing. And so, uh, and the
beer tastes really good. So,
thank you, Mr. Chairman.
>> I'd echo those, too. And especially the
the story you told me the other night
about the structural issues you had and
how you fixed that. That's
was a amazing story. How about a vote?
I
>> I I
>> I
the recommendation of the finance
committee to the governing body. Next
money will be to approve. Next item
>> number 16 resolution reappropriating the
fiscal year 2026 budget of the city of
Cheyenne according to the provisions of
Wyoming state statute 16-4-112
and 16-4-113.
>> The staff report. Madam treasure.
>> Good afternoon. Hello chairman, members
of the committee. My name is Robin Lman.
I'm the city treasurer. Today before you
is the second reappropriation of fiscal
year 2026 budget. I've outlined the
details in my memo, but I'll walk
through the main items first. On
December 8th of last year, the governing
body approved a resolution authorizing a
3% cost of living salary adjustment for
eligible full-time and part-time
employees of the city of Cheyenne. To
put that into effect, this
reappropriation increases the budget
line items for full-time employees for
the remaining six months of fiscal year
2026 by $554,652
from general fund reserves and $160,770
from all other funds. Because part-time
hours are less predictable, we'll bring
forward any reappropriation needed for
to facilitate this cost of living
increase. At the end of the year, there
are three additional general fund
requests totaling $86,520.
These include $23,270
for Granicus Peak Agenda Management and
Foya solution software subscriptions,
replacing ARPA funds that have now
expired and were previously used for
this purpose. This item was
inadvertently omitted from the city
clerk's fiscal year 2026 budget request.
$5,000 for appraisal services related to
the former Larry County Senior Center at
211 Thes Avenue and 58,250
to reimburse Larmy County for rent and
utilities for office space leased on the
3rd and fifth floors of the US Bank
building from October to December of
2025 of which 47,750
is rent and 10,500 is utilities.
Now turning to the non-general fund
requests. First, we are requesting
reappropriation for several new grants
that have been received and are outlined
in your packet. We have also requesting
12,769
from the solid waste fund reserves to
purchase a new copier for the transfer
station. After this purchase, we will
only have three copers remaining under
lease for the city entire city. the
copier at the Botanic Gardens, the
copier currently housed in community
recreation and events admin office that
was previously used in the IT print shop
and the NOS's copier. We plan to request
one-time funds in the upcoming budget to
replace the Botanic Gardens and the CRA
admin copiers because their leases both
expire next fiscal year. Once this
happens, the city will own all of our
copers um with the exception of transit
and NPOS's copiers that are grant
funded. Uh the specific purpose option
tax fund. We are requesting $300,000 in
grant match ballot funds for the Dunbar
Ballfields lighting project. 3.6 million
for city contract 8274 for Cheyenne
Leeds for administration of the large
gap finance gap finance program which
addresses financing gaps in eligible
economic development projects and 2.2
million in carryover reserves that were
not included in the prior
reappropriation consisting of $14,046
for expenses associated with fire truck
ballot, 200,000 for greenway maintenance
and 1,986,332
for city road projects. From the
fiduciary fund, we are requesting 16,760
from the historic preservation board
account to pay for the 2025 Christmas
ornaments and repairs to the historic
airport fountain. These funds were
generated by and belong to the historic
preservation board with the city only
serving in a fiduciary capacity.
Finally, we are requesting $83,750
for various line items in the
miscellaneous agency fund. Each of these
amounts are is supported by existing
reserve balances in their respected
accounts. The applicable directors I
believe are here today and can address
any specific questions you may have and
I will stand for questions as well.
Thank you.
>> Committee have any questions for our
treasur?
>> Go out to the public. Any public comment
on this item?
Seeing none. Can I get a motion?
>> Mr. Chair, I move to adopt.
>> Second.
>> Motion from Councilman White to adopt
and seconded by Councilman Wolf. Any
further discussion?
>> Uh, Councilman Wolf.
>> Mr. Chairman, through you. Um, I just
want to note I u I talked to the
treasurer before this to make sure I
understand what this is. This is this is
actually quarterly routine business for
um the treasur's office and the council.
Um and it shows how
incredibly complex our financings
are and our financial arrangements. Um,
but I also would would want to note that
uh last week we heard the results of our
audit, which were an absolutely clean
audit. Um, and it's really a testament
to the treasurer and her staff. uh and
the work they do to to keep the city's
finances under uh full control and and
um just we we on the council really
appreciate uh uh madam treasur what you
do and and how well you do it. So thank
you.
>> Yeah. Thank you. Any [clears throat] uh
other comments from
Councilman Dr. Emmens?
Ready
for a vote?
>> I I
>> I
>> Okay. The recommendation to the
governing body next Monday will be to
adopt. Next item
>> number 20. Resolution authorizing the
submission of an application by the city
of Cheyenne for state funding for the
office of state lands and investment
unmet housing grant.
>> Staff report.
Good afternoon. Amber Ash, chief of
staff for the city of Cheyenne. Um, so
this resolution is for Habitat for
Humanity to apply for an unmet housing
grant. Um,
Dan wasn't able to be here today. Um but
this application is due the 26th. Um he
is asking for um the amount to be
reduced from $1 million on the request
to $500,000 is my understanding. So if
we could please amend that today and
make that correction. I would appreciate
it.
I'm happy to try to answer any
questions.
>> Councilman White.
>> Mr. Chair, I would move to amend. Oh,
sorry.
Sorry. I'll uh I'll wait for the motion
before making the amendment.
>> Any public comment?
>> Hi, Mr. Chair. I'm Daffhne. I uh work at
Habitat for Humanity. I'm the
development director. Um and we're
actually applying um in conjunction with
Magic City. Uh they are the owners of
the land. Um and so uh we received unmet
housing needs through the city uh for
our current uh project at Ponghorn
Crossing uh which has been wonderful
being able to get a lot of that
infrastructure done. We're able to
increase our rate of building because of
that because we weren't having to fund
raise for as long. Uh so it's been a
really um awesome opportunity for us to
not just build two or three houses a
year, but to build 12 this year uh with
hopes of homeowners moving in before
Thanksgiving. Um, so we are excited
about our partnership with Magic City to
be able to do something similar um and
hopefully be able to get some of those
infrastructure costs paid for so that we
can um continue to build at a faster
pace and uh continue to meet that
growing need of um affordable housing in
Cheyenne. So um I would welcome any
questions and uh we're just so
appreciative of the opportunity.
>> Thank you. Any questions?
Any further public comment?
Good afternoon, Mr. Chairman.
[clears throat] Excuse me. I'm Jeff
Gardner. I'm the CEO at Magic City
Enterprises, uh, 1780 Westland Road. and
and certainly not to repeat anything
that Daphne said, but uh this this
project came about uh through through a
board member of Magic City and in
talking with Habitat and knowing the
needs that we had. Uh we are so excited
to be partnering with Habitat. Uh we
appreciate the consideration of the
application and and I'm sure it doesn't
hurt that uh the request is smaller than
it than it initially was. Uh that's
because the the bid the the final bid
came in lower than we expected. So
that's good news. Just a few things
about it. This project certainly fits
within the parameters of the unmet
housing needs. Um the the request is for
infrastructure primarily curb, gutter,
sewer, water, those kinds of things. Um,
you know, as I said, this uh this
partnership is something that we've
gotten a lot of really positive feedback
on to uh well-known nonprofits in the
community who are, you know, looking to
work together to meet uh the needs of of
many people. uh Magic City in
particular, we're looking at uh actually
not looking at we have been moving from
a larger congregate setting down to
smaller, more independent, more private
kinds of living spaces for people with
intellectual and developmental
disabilities and certainly the unmet
need for uh families who who work with
Habitat. So, six of the the 12 units
will be for use for with with Magic City
and and our supports and services, six
of which will be for Habitat families.
So, it's a really unique project. We
don't know that there's another one
across the country and we think that it
could be a template for, you know,
future collaborations uh between Habitat
and Magic City and and possibly others.
So, uh, I don't want to take a lot of
your time, but would certainly stand for
any questions and, uh, thank you again
for your consideration.
>> Committee have any questions for Mr.
Gardner?
>> Well, any further public comment?
>> Can I get a motion?
>> Mr. Chair, I move to adopt.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman White,
seconded by Dr. Emmens. Uh,
any further comment,
>> Mr. Chair? I would move to amend the um
resolution
and
um
I believe it's in the one two three
fifth whereas to make that amount
$500,000
instead of the $1 million that is
currently listed.
>> Second.
>> It's been motioned and seconded to
amend. Oh,
any further discussion on the amendment?
Back on the main motion. Ready for a
vote?
>> No.
>> Got a
>> vote on the amendment.
>> I
>> The amendment is passed. Now we're back
on the main motion. Any further
discussion?
Ready
to vote on the main motion?
>> I I
>> the recommendation of the finance
committee next meeting of the governing
body will be to adopt. Next
item
>> number 22B, human services agreement
between the city of Cheyenne and United
Way of Larmy County to provide funding
to community agencies and monitor
performance of community programs from
the 2019 to 2022 optional 1% sales tax
fund.
>> Staff report
>> Vicky Neichek Public Works. This is a
contract between the city and United Way
of Laramie County. If you'll notice in
the contract, there is an exhibit A that
lists all of the um the distributes, I
should say, of the overage money. The
the money that um funds this contract is
overage money from the 2019 to 2022
fifth penny sales tax. We do have some
United Way representatives here to
answer any questions you have, but this
um request was made from United Way via
the Human Services Advisory Council and
was approved at that meeting.
>> Happy to answer any questions.
>> Any questions for the director?
>> Councilman Emmens, you can go ahead.
>> Thank you. Um my question is how we
determine which of the um community
organizations are involved in this.
>> I'll start that through you, chair. Um
we have we do pay United Way $10,500
each year to make these decisions for
us. Um they have a board. I'll let uh
Chris Whitfield respond more
specifically to that that question.
Mr. Chairman, I'm Chris Whitfield. I'm
the executive director for United Way.
Um, so we have and I've got with me uh
Tia Fitzgerald. She is um uh our staff
liaison that works with a independent
community-led community leader committee
that um looks at the application
process. Uh we had about 30 applicants
this year. Um, in our our year is a
little bit different than the cities.
Ours is a fiscal year. Y'alls begins in
July. So, because of the crossover, we
added four new uh agencies. Um, and I
believe at the bottom of your um report
may be the the newest ones that have
been added on. So, the new ones this
year were uh Friday Food Bag Foundation,
Community Action, Lions Disability
Transport Service, and Veterans Rock. So
they they make the decisions um on who
gets funded and then comes to our board
with recommendations and then we take
that to the health and human services or
human services advisory board for
approval.
>> Any questions for Miss Mcfield?
No.
Any further public comment?
Yes, ma'am.
>> Um, I'm Daffhne Sandwell. Again, I work
at Habitat for Humanity. Um, and we're
one of the nonprofit partners with
United Way and have been for several
years and uh they've been a great
resource for us to get new programming
uh started. So, it's been very
beneficial for uh our community to
collaborate with others in Cheyenne and
meet the needs of our community. Thank
you.
>> Thank you. Any further public comment?
Seeing none, can I get a motion?
>> Mr. Chair, I move to approve in an
amount not to exceed $100,000.
>> Second.
>> It's been motioned by Councilman White,
seconded by Councilman Wolf. Uh any
further discussion?
Can I get a vote?
>> I
been motion and approved for by the
finance committee to the governing body
to acknowledge receipt
to approve.
Next item
>> number 22 C. professional services
agreement between the city of Cheyenne,
Cheyenne Metropolitan Planning
Organization and Stantech Consulting
Services Incorporated for the East
Allison Road Corridor study from no
funds.
>> Staff report.
>> Mr. Chair, um thank you. Um this is I'm
Christopher Yani with the um MO and I'm
the MO director. Uh this uh professional
uh service agreement is uh with
Stantech. Uh we had advertised uh and um
posted this on our website um for um
proposals. We received seven propo
proposals uh for this project and we had
a selection committee go through all of
those and select Stantech. Um after
negotiating with the Stantech on the uh
price so it's uh to not to exceed uh
199,5144
and this project is uh the consent of
the project is from East Allison Road
from um US85 South Gley Highway to
College Drive. the po uh portion of it
will be from uh US85 to Avenue C.
That'll be a 30% um design and then from
there to
uh the existing Avenue C and NARA
industrial park will be a 10% uh design
to uh determine whether or not the uh
road can be configured in that area. So,
this is to improve the um the road in
that area for the public in in this
location.
Uh if you have any questions, I'd be
happy to answer
>> questions from the committee to staff.
Any public comment?
Seeing none, can I get a motion?
>> Mr. Chair, I move to approve in an
amount not to exceed $199,5144.
>> Second.
>> Good motion by Councilman White,
seconded by Councilman Wolf. Any further
discussion?
>> Any vote?
>> I
been approved by the finance committee
to the governing body to approve. Next
item
>> number 23B, consideration of bid number
E-11-26
for Microsoft data center product
licensing and virtual infrastructure for
the city of Cheyenne information
technology division from the general
fund.
>> Staff,
>> Mr. Chair, Dustin Swall, City IT, the
bid before you to purchase Microsoft
data center licensing for our two data
centers we currently maintain uh for the
city. Uh it's a onetime cost perpetual
license. We'll cover us for the next 10
years. It's a one cost you're seeing. Um
it makes basically gives us two primary
benefits. The first thing it gives us is
the ability to run as many Microsoft
servers as we'd like to in our virtual
environment. So we don't have to worry
about licensing each individual server
every time we spin one up. Uh gives us a
cart launch as long as it's Microsoft
server. We're good to go. Um up to 2025
which is the newest one they're just set
to release for the server versioning.
And it also and the more important one
for us, it also enables us to utilize
their HyperV software which is their
hypervisor virtual environment software.
So we have used for years for I don't
know 15 years plus I think we've been a
VMware environment for our virtual
environment. That's what we've run as
VMware software. U VMware got bought out
by Broadcom unfortunately. So, the last
four years it's doubled every year. This
the maintenance and the the licensing
cost and this year the quote was almost
$70,000
uh which is wild. We were paying around
10 four years ago. So, we decided that's
no longer palatable and it's just going
to keep going up. They've kind of met
the writing's kind of on the wall that
they're going to continue raising that
every year. So, we decided we need to
look somewhere else and Microsoft offers
the HyperV along with their data center
licensing. So, it's kind of kills two
birds with one stone. um allows us to
upgrade our servers and run all of our
servers in our virtual environment. Also
allows us to upgrade our SQL servers to
the newest version in this licensing. Uh
and it gives us the right to use that
HyperV to get off of VMware and go onto
this and it's a much cheaper license for
a 10-year term for perpetual license. So
uh I will stand for any questions
>> questions from the committee to the
staff.
>> Uh Council through you. Uh thank you. Um
so do we do we make a lumpsum payment to
them uh or do we is this incrementalized
over the life of the
>> Yeah, Mr. Chair, for you the the payment
to them will be lump sum and then uh the
finance folks the smarter folks than I
will be breaking it down in the budgets
over the next 10 years to kind of break
it out of the budgeting cycle for 10
years across of it. Um they probably
could speak to that better than I could,
but the lump sum will happen to the bit
to the winning bid. Yeah. right off for
the petrol licensing.
>> Any further questions?
Got a public comment.
>> Seeing none, can I get a motion?
>> Mr. Chair, I move to accept the bid from
Hypertch USA, Inc. in an amount not to
exceed $239,577.88.
>> Second.
Moved by Councilman White, second by
Councilman Wolf. Any further discussion?
Ready for a vote?
>> I
>> recommendation of the finance committee
to the governing body next Monday will
be to approve. Next item.
Resolution authorizing the submission of
an application by the state funding
through the office of state lands and
investment for rodeo grounds pedestrian
transportation infrastructure grant and
authorizing the execution and submittal
of all necessary documents in support of
the application.
>> Staff report.
>> Uh good afternoon. Amber Ash, chief of
staff. Um before you today is a
resolution authorizing submission of an
application to the Office of State Land
and Investments for a Rodeo Ground
Pedestrian Transportation Infrastructure
Grant. Um during the 2023 general
session, the legislature appropriated $4
million um to the Office of State Lands
and Investments for the purpose of
providing grants for infrastructure
um related to qualifying special events
conducted on the grounds of any indoor
or outdoor rodeo facility with a total
seating capacity of at least 7500.
Um, this grant request is for four4
million to build a fully enclosed
pre-fabricated trust bridge that spans
both I25 and Hines Boulevard. It'll have
a minimum width of 12 ft to allow for
two-way pedestrian flow. And the design
features will include ADA compliant
ramps with appropriate slopes,
handrails, and surface treatments to
ensure accessibility for all users. Um,
this bridge will connect to um the event
parking lot um on approximately 36.5
acres of land on the eastern edge of FE
Warren Air Force Base. Um, and will
accommodate approximately 2,800 parking
stalls, including 42 padded ADA
accessible stalls and a designated area
for bus pickup and drop off. Um the
project will replace an off-site lot
that is approximately 2.5 miles
southwest of Frontier Park currently
known as the Bol lot. Um this bol lot is
on leased land owned by the Air Force
that is proposed to be converted into
housing. Um the preliminary phase one
design and environmental assessment for
this project have been completed. Um
this grant does require a onetoone
match. Um, Cheyenne Frontier Days will
contribute $2 million. Larmy County will
contribute 1 million and the city of
Cheyenne will be contributing the
remaining 1 million um based on your
approval today and Monday. I'm happy to
answer any questions you may have. Um, I
also have with me today Mary Kay Hill
who is the CFD board of directors
chairwoman. Um, city engineer Tom Cobb
and economic resource administrator uh
Libby. Um, I'm really sorry, Libby.
Not quite sure on the last name.
>> So,
>> any questions for from the committee to
the staff?
>> Um, Councilman Wolf, Mr. Chairman,
through you. Thank you. Um, thanks for
bringing this to us. Um,
and, um, so who controls this land now
where this parking lot is? Um so the the
land where the parking lot is proposed
um belongs with Epie Warren Air Force
Base. Um the mayor did deliver the gift
package last Friday. Um and so we are
are working um with both the base and um
um with our congressional
representatives on that gift package.
Council White,
>> I just had a quick uh clarification
question. Uh Mr. Chair, I don't know if
Mr. Cobb can answer this or not, but in
looking at the diagram, uh when I went
to the public uh meeting that was at the
White Auditorium, gosh, must have been a
year ago now. Um
when when I attended that there were two
schools of thought. One was to have the
bridge go from the area that we see here
in this depiction across
um I25
coming back onto around 8th Avenue. And
then there was also a second option at
that uh that was uh given at that
meeting where the uh bridge would have
gone uh a little bit north to there I
think uh kind of by the country club and
then um crossing I25 there. So, this one
looks like the the uh choice was made to
have it uh come across I25
and then um end around the area of 8th
Avenue or probably a little bit north
where those um bronze statues are uh
which I think CFD wanted to kind of have
that be the the uh new kind of front
gate entrance. Am I correct in that, Mr.
Cobb?
Chairman through you to Councilman
White. Yes sir, that is correct. We
actually did three alternatives. So when
you look, it's for the NEBA analysis. So
you have to do a no build option and
then two alternatives. So those were
placed in there, but the option was made
to cross I25 just north of the statues
near the area where the overhead
structure is at the interstate.
>> Thanks for that clarification.
>> Uh Councilman Wolf, Mr. Excuse
me.
>> Through the chair. Yes. Uh um will um
will this design accommodate golf carts
and shuttle carts and other things to
move people who have mobility
challenges?
>> Mr. Cobb.
>> Chairman through you to Councilman Wolf.
Yes, sir. That's the plan. And again,
the photo that you see is a concept
rendering. Um the actual plan, just so
everyone knows, all the landing and ramp
systems will be actually within the
interstate property. We're staying out
of FE Warren. It'll go on to it
eventually, but we're actually
containing ourselves within that
property and we've coordinated with W
dot to that regard because we didn't
want to complicate the gift package if
that makes sense. Any
further questions from committee to
staff?
Dr. Emmens.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chair. I have two
questions. Um, one is what is a gift
package and two is um in reference to
the meeting that that Councilman White
spoke about. I was at that also and I
know there was concerns about um going
on to the golf course land. So does this
eliminate this option eliminate that
issue? Thank you,
>> Mr. Cub.
>> Mr. Chairman, through you to to Dr.
Emmens. Dr. Emmens, yes, the option was
eliminated to go through the golf course
and as I've discussed with them on
several occasions. There was a plan done
around 2015 that there eventually is
some going to be some connection with
the greenway to some of this area. where
it goes right now is undetermined, but
it's so that's what got everybody, I
guess I would say, for lack of a better
term, a little riled up. Um, but
nobody's going through the golf course
for the this is not nothing to do with
that right now. Ma'am,
>> another question, Dr. Evans.
>> Uh, my other question was the gift
package. Can somebody explain to me what
that is?
>> Miss Hill.
>> Mr. Chairman Mary Kay Hill. I am the
chairman of the board of directors for
Cheyenne Frontier Days. Um I will answer
the question by backing up a little bit
and give you some background on the
project. We've been working on this for
about four years coming up uh in May.
First approached by the base um saying
we think we can work out a partnership
if you want to use this this ground for
parking. Um where can we go from there?
And so the concept of parking on that
piece of ground which is and I apologize
because I'm really bad on northsoutheast
west directions but if you go north of
what's kind of the base recreation
compound and bordering interstate 25
that's the ground we're talking about
comes up to the fence line for the
country club. Uh the question then how
do we get people from the parking lot
into Frontier Days and the bridge is
obviously part of that solution.
Something that's been on the Cheyenne
Frontier Days uh planning wish list for
50 60 years. It's been a long time
because as you're well aware we're quite
landlocked. So that's when conversations
began with the base. This appropriation
came along uh maybe 18 months into our
conversations and is not specifically
for our project but as you can see many
of the criteria fit Cheyenne Frontier
Days quite well. So the project involves
multiple players at all variety of
governmental levels. We're coordinating
with the city of Cheyenne who obviously
owns the frontier days piece. We're
coordinating with the county
commissioners who are the
have jurisdiction over the base piece of
the property. We're working with the air
force u base civil engineering folks as
well as the secretary of the air force.
We're working with the department of
transportation and the federal highway
administration all of whom have pieces
in the project. And I um can take up a
lot of your time by going into those,
but just know all of those players have
been involved fairly extensively at
various steps. The gift package,
Councilwoman um Emmens, in order for um
the city and Cheyen Frontier Days to
construct a parking lot, there are what
the Air Force defines as improvements to
the ground. And in order for us to
execute those improvements, there's
something in the Air Force vernacular
that is a gift um
a gift package. So what is represented
in the gift package is on behalf of the
various players the city of Cheyenne
offers to make those improvements
um improved access roadways
drainage uh fencing all variety of um
engineering requirements. Gravel to boat
to be specific. nothing paved but gravel
um on that piece of ground in order for
it to be used for a parking lot. As uh
Tom Cobb said, the actual bridge, which
is the focus of this grant application,
is to be constructed on federal right of
way across the interstate and then
dropping down onto the Cheyenne Frontier
Day grants.
>> Further questions for Miss Hill.
>> Uh Councilman Wolf.
>> Yes. Mr. Chairman, through you. Um,
thank you for coming. Nice to see you.
Uh,
is
I'm just thinking about all the
potential uses for the parking lot and
the bridge. And I guess sort of the
first one is is this only going to be
used during frontier days or or is this
kind of a year round parking lot and are
you I guess the related question is if
it's only for frontier days do you lock
off that uh bridge for the rest of the
year?
>> Miss Hill.
>> Uh Mr. Chairman, the uh gift proposal
gives the air force the authority to
determine uses for the bridge. Once we
started, originally the conversation was
limited to Cheyenne Frontier Days, but
once we started talking about that and
the uh the benefits of a physical
connection between the base and the
community, um multiple
hoped for uses were identified, all of
which um are likely to begin most
earnestly once the once the bridge is
there. So um Mr. Cob talked about the
greenway. Certainly there are have been
discussions over the years about
greenway access on the base, but it's
also an air force base. Um, and there
are security provisions. So, um, each
use would need to be identified in
cooperation with the air force base and
whomever chose to use it. At frontier
days, that would not be our call. though
we are responsible would be responsible
for the security certainly during the
event and um the city would dictate
terms for any other uses beyond that.
>> Any further questions from the committee
to staff or the applicant?
>> Any public comment?
Can I get a motion?
>> Mr. Chair, I move to adopt.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman White,
seconded by Dr. Edmmonds. Any further
discussion?
>> Ready to vote?
>> I I
>> the recommendation of the finance
committee to the governing body next
Monday will be to adopt. Seeing there's
no more business from front of the
finance committee, we are adjourned.